

Contact Details

Gabriel Díaz Iturry

M gabriel.diaz.iturry

in /in/gabriel-diaz-iturry

○ /gabo-di

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue

English: Advanced Portuguese: Fluent

Esperanto: Intermediate

Díaz Gabriel Iturry

Physicist - Data Scientist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Nonlinear Dynamics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data and the use of statistical tools to compare data to models. I currently work for CAP4GI, writing a Julia repository for ecological/agricultural research.

Experience

April 2024 - Present

Julia/Fortran Developer:

- Open source Julia repository for ecological research in the group CAP4GI.
- Use of Fortran code AquaCrop from FAO.

Jan 2023 - April 2024t

Independent Researcher:

- Research in areas of Time Series analysis using Artificial Intelligence and Data Driven Modeling.
- Web developer, in charge of integrating the AI code with the Web page.

May 2021 - Apr 2023

Data Scientist, Physicist:

- Reproduce state-of-the-art reasearch.
- Deliver the models in a clear and robust interfarce for user consumption.
- Optimization using Operations Research and Heuristics methods for several projects.

Feb 2017 - Feb 2021

Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Research projects include:

- Anomalous Diffusion on Classical Systems.
- Bifurcation Analysis.
- Quantum to Classical transition.

Education

2017 - 2021

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil.

2015 - 2017

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade Estadual de São Paulo (UNESP) São Paulo, Brazil.

Skills

Technical

Scientific Research, Scientific Computing, Simulations, Neural Networks, Machine Learning

Software Development

Python, R, Julia, Fortran, Golang, Mathematica, MatLab. PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn, XGBoost, CatBoost.